https://electricity.ca/legal/privacy/

Hit enter to search or ESC to close Hit submit to search MembershipBecome a MemberWhy Join CEA?The National Voice of Electricity CanadaBenefits of MembershipMembership CategoriesCouncils and CommitteesOverviewCouncilsCommitteesBecome a Sustainable Electricity CompanyThe BrandEligibilitySteps to EarningSustainable Electricity CompaniesMembership ListMembersCorporate PartnersAssociate PartnersLeadOverviewPowering Canada’s EconomyOverviewBuilding Canada’s Clean Growth FutureInvesting in Tomorrow’s InfrastructureBridging the Innovation GapProtecting the Power GridProtecting Our EnvironmentOverviewClimate Change AdaptationEnergy EfficiencyAir QualitySpecies ProtectionPartnering for a Better FutureOverviewPartnering with Indigenous CommunitiesAdvancing North American PartnershipsCanada’s Electricity SectorCentre of ExcellenceDeliverOverviewSustainabilityOverviewSustainable Electricity ProgramBecome a Sustainable Electricity CompanyNational Electricity MonthPower of ArtHealth and SafetyNational Lineworker Appreciation DayAnalytics and Reliability ProgramOverviewBuy Reliability and Performance ReportsLearnOverviewHistory of ElectricityElectricity TodayOverviewGenerating ElectricityNorth American Power GridFuture of ElectricityOverviewElectricity RatesCarbon Capture StorageEnergy StorageSmart TechnologyLibraryAwardsOverviewOccupational Health & SafetyOverviewNominate someone for a Lifesaving AwardSustainable ElectricityOverviewApply for a Sustainable Electricity AwardElectric VehicleOverviewApply for an EV AwardPast RecipientsNews & EventsBlogAbout CEAContactCareersLog inJoin CEAPodcastFrançais
Skip to contentHome / Legal / Privacy
Sidebar  Privacy Privacy
Terms of Use
Contributors Our Privacy Statement explains what personal information and user data we collect when you visit our website. We also explain why we collect this information, what we do with it, and how we protect your privacy by protecting that information.For the purposes of this Privacy Statement, “personal information” means any information relating to an identified or identifiable individual who is the subject of the information and “user data” means information automatically collected by the website or service providers about your use of the website.When you visit www.electricity.ca you can learn about the evolving electricity business in Canada, engage with our events and content, and purchase reports.  If you are employed by one of our members you may also request access to CEA’s Directory.The website uses third party service providers to assist with analyzing visits to the website and to process payments.When you visit our websiteInformation we collectWhen you visit www.electricity.ca, we collect information about your visit that does not identify you personally, using a session cookie, which is a small file that is attached to your browser’s memory.The information about all the visits to our website tells us the type of computer, browser, and web service our website visitors are using. We also know the date, time, and the pages viewed of each visit. When you leave the site, the cookie stops collecting information.We use Google Analytics to collect this user data and analyze the use of the website. The information collected is sent to Google Analytics’ servers in an anonymous form. For more information please see: www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/You can opt-out of analytics activity by setting your browser to notify you when a cookie is sent and block analytics cookies if desired. Please consult your browser’s Help Menu for instructions. Visiting our website with analytics cookies disabled will have no significant impact on your browsing experience.What we do with that informationCollecting information about website visits helps us design the site to suit your needs and to improve users’ experience.How we protect your privacyWe ensure that the user data we collect is aggregated so that it cannot be used to track any particular device or individual or identify you personally. We do not share or disclose the user data collected with third parties other than as described above.When you volunteer your personal information onlineInformation we collectWhen you register for an event, subscribe to a newsletter, comment on a blog post, or share a webpage to a social media channel, you may enter your name, email address, or your social media information.You acknowledge that we do not control the social media services identified on our website or your profiles on these services, and that we do not establish privacy settings or rules for how your personal information on those services will be used which will be subject to the applicable social media service’s terms and conditions and your current privacy settings on such social media service.If you decide to register, log into, “like” or interact with our website or events through social media services (eg. Facebook, Instagram, Twitter), you will be assuming the risk that the information you provide on that service may be viewed or used by third parties for any purpose. You agree that we are not responsible for any acts or omissions by these social media service providers.What we do with that informationIf you subscribe to a newsletter or other notification, we will use your email address for the purpose for which you provided it.  We only keep your information so we can follow up with you, if necessary.How we protect your privacyWe keep your information completely confidential. We do not rent, share, or trade it with anyone else. We will not use it to send you information that you did not specifically request.When you buy a reportInformation we collectWhen you purchase an Analytics report online, the transaction is processed by Moneris through SSL-encrypted technology (see https://www.moneris.com/en/Legal/Privacy-Notice for more information). This means that your credit card and other payment information is transmitted and maintained securely.What we do with that informationWe use this information to complete the transaction and deliver your purchase.How we protect your privacyAfter your transaction is complete, we do not store your credit card or other payment information. We do retain other information about the transaction including your name and the date of purchase as required to maintain records and in accordance with applicable law.When you access the DirectoryThe CEA publishes an online Directory of its member companies. Employees of CEA member companies with a valid email address provided by the CEA member can request access to the CEA Directory.You agree that you will only access the Directory while you are an employee of a CEA member company. You further agree that you will not reproduce the Directory, distribute, or publish the Directory without the express written consent of CEA.Information we collectIn order to view the Directory, you will be required to create an account using an email address provided to you by a CEA member. In order to verify your email address and create an account,  CEA will email you a temporary password.After you login using the temporary password you will be invited to create an account which requires you to provide your full name, email address, and job title. You will also be required to create a password. If you choose to create an account, you agree that CEA can store your account information and password information.  We will also collect information about the frequency with which you access the Directory and the portions of it you access.What we do with that informationWe will use your account and password information to manage your account and to provide access to the Directory.We will store your username and password for as long as required to provide access to the Directory.We will also collect information about your accesses to the Directory including the date, time, and pages viewed.  This information will be aggregated with accesses by other users and analyzed to improve the Directory.How we protect your privacyWe keep information about your account completely confidential. We do not rent, share, or trade it with anyone else. We will not use it to send you information that you did not specifically request other than informational updates related to your account.Retention of Personal InformationWe may retain personal information we collect from you for as long as reasonably necessary (and allowed by law) to administer our website, provide access to the Directory, manage events and discussions, facilitate the purchase of Reports, and other services as requested by you.Personal information and user data may also be retained as reasonably necessary to comply with our legal obligations and regulatory requirements, resolve disputes, and enforce our Privacy Statement and Terms of Use.Security of InformationThe website employs a number of safeguards intended to mitigate the risk of unauthorized access or disclosure of this information.CEA, however, cannot guarantee the security of the information collected and received. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors may compromise the security of user information at any time.Citizens of the European Union This site was not specifically designed for use in the European Union or its jurisdictions.Changes to our Privacy Statement We may change and update this Privacy Statement from time to time. Your continued access to the website following the posting of changes to this Privacy Statement constitutes your acceptance and agreement to the changes. If you object to any of the changes to this Privacy Statement, please stop accessing the website. Visitors to the website should review this page periodically for changes.Your rights under the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (PIPEDA)PIPEDA requires CEA to collect, use, or disclose your personal information by fair and lawful means, with your consent, and only for purposes that are stated and reasonable.CEA may only collect personal information that is essential to the business transaction. You should still be able to complete the transaction, even if you refuse to give out more personal information than is necessary.CEA is also obliged to protect your personal information through appropriate security measures, and to destroy it when it’s no longer needed for the original purposes.You have the right to expect the personal information CEA holds about you to be accurate, complete, and up-to-date. That means you have a right to see it, and to ask for corrections if they got it wrong.Questions about your privacy?Contact Laura Cui info@electricity.ca Connect Stay informed Keep a finger on the pulse - simply sign up to our mailing list, follow us on social media or drop us a line!Current AffairsReceive our newsletter, Current affairs, directly to your inbox. Sign Up Now 5FollowConnect with us on social media to stay informed and get involved.
ContactGet in touch if you want to find out more about our membership benefits Contact Us 5
Your privacy matters to us.We use cookies to offer you a better experience and analyze how our site is being used. By visiting electricity.ca, you accept these terms. Read more. Got it
